The next data manipulation keyword we are
going to look at is the DELETE keyword.
The DELETE keyword deletes records from a
table.
It does not delete an object such as a table.
If you want to delete an entire object, you
will want to use the DROP keyword, which is
covered elsewhere in this course.
I have a file open that has both a SELECT
statement and a DELETE statement.
Before running a DELETE statement, it is always
a good idea to run a SELECT statement on the
table you are about to change.
Doing this will ensure it is the table you
want to delete records from because, as stated
elsewhere in this course, these changes cannot
be undone.
I will run the SELECT statement, and indeed
this is the table that has the records I want
to delete.
The DELETE statement itself is very simple.
All this contains is DELETE FROM and then
the table to be emptied.
If we wanted to use a WHERE clause to limit
what is being deleted, we can.
That said, I will select and execute this
DELETE statement, and this table has been
emptied.